<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fly.io on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/fly.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fly.io on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/fly.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fly Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/240314/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/240314/</guid>
      <description>Interested to explore Fly Kubernetes after being accepted into the closed beta.&#xA;The folks at Fly are innovative in their technology uses and, having been a long-time Kubernetes user, I was intrigued to learn that Fly.io has implemented Kubernetes atop Fly.&#xA;My first Deployment failed:&#xA;Authentication required to access image &amp;#34;ghcr.io/{image}&amp;#34; It was confirmed to me that FKS does not support pulling from private registries. The solution is pull-tag-push images to registry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus Exporters for fly.io and Vultr</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220520/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220520/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a roll building utilities this week. I developed a Service Health dashboard for my &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo;, a Prometheus Exporter for Fly.io and today, a Prometheus Exporter for Vultr. This is motivated by the fear that I will forget a deployed Cloud resource and incur a horrible bill.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve no written several Prometheus Exporters for cloud platforms:&#xA;Prometheus Exporter for GCP Prometheus Exporter for Linode Prometheus Exporter for Fly.io Prometheus Exporter for Vultr Each of them monitors resource deployments and produces resource count metrics that can be scraped by Prometheus and alerted with Alertmanager.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fly.io</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/210412/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/210412/</guid>
      <description>I spent some time over the weekend understanding Fly.io. It&amp;rsquo;s always fascinating to me how many smart people are building really neat solutions. Fly.io is subtly different to other platforms that I use (Kubernetes, GCP, DO, Linode) and I&amp;rsquo;ve found the Fly.io team to be highly responsive and helpful to my noob questions.&#xA;One of the team&amp;rsquo;s posts, Docker without Docker surfaced in my Feedly feed (hackernews) and it piqued my interest.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
