<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linode on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/linode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linode on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/linode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secure (TLS) gRPC services with LKE</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/230215/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/230215/</guid>
      <description>NOTE cert-manager is a better solution to what follows.
I wrote about deploying Secure (TLS) gRPC services with Vultr Kubernetes Engine (VKE). This week, I&amp;rsquo;ve reproduced this deployment using Linode Kubernetes Engine (LKE).
Thanks to the consistency provided by Kubernetes, the Kubernetes programming is almost identical. The main differences are between the CLI&amp;rsquo;s provided by these platforms. Both are good. They&amp;rsquo;re just different.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to include the linode-cli commands I&amp;rsquo;m using in this post as I found it slightly more quirky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus AlertManager</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/191219/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/191219/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I discussed a Linode Prometheus Exporter and tantalized use of Prometheus AlertManager.
Success:
Configure The process is straightforward although I found the Prometheus (config) documentation slightly unwieldy to navigate :-(
The overall process is documented.
Here are the steps I took:
Configure Prometheus Configure AlertManager Revise Docker Compose Configure Prometheus Added the following to prometheus.yml:
rule_files: - &amp;#34;/etc/alertmanager/rules/linode.yml&amp;#34; alerting: alertmanagers: - scheme: http static_configs: - targets: - &amp;#34;alertmanager:9093&amp;#34; Rules must be defined in separate rules files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linode Prometheus Exporter</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/191218/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/191218/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy using Prometheus and have toyed around with it for some time particularly in combination with Kubernetes. I signed up with Linode [referral] compelled by the addition of a managed Kubernetes service called Linode Kubernetes Engine (LKE). I have an anxiety that I&amp;rsquo;ll inadvertently leave resources running (unused) on a cloud platform. Instead of refreshing the relevant billing page, it struck me that Prometheus may (not yet proven) help.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
