<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wasm on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/wasm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wasm on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/wasm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WASM Cloud Functions</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200617/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200617/</guid>
      <description>Following on from waPC &amp;amp; Protobufs and a question on Stack Overflow about Cloud Functions, I was compelled to try running WASM on Cloud Functions no JavaScript.
I wanted to reuse the WASM waPC functions that I&amp;rsquo;d written in Rust as described in the other post. Cloud Functions does not (yet!?) provide a Rust runtime and so I&amp;rsquo;m using the waPC Host for Go in this example.
It works!
PARAMS=$(printf &amp;#39;{&amp;#34;a&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;real&amp;#34;:39,&amp;#34;imag&amp;#34;:3},&amp;#34;b&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;real&amp;#34;:39,&amp;#34;imag&amp;#34;:3}}&amp;#39; | base64) TOKEN=$(gcloud auth print-identity-token) echo &amp;#34;{ \&amp;#34;filename\&amp;#34;:\&amp;#34;complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>waPC &amp; Protobufs</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200612/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200612/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m hacking around with a solution that combines WASM and Google Trillian.
Ultimately, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to ship WASM (binaries) to a Trillian personality and then invoke (exported) functions on them. Some this was borne from the interesting exploration of Krustlet and its application of wascc.
I&amp;rsquo;m still booting into WASM but it&amp;rsquo;s a very interesting technology that has most interesting potential outside the browser. Some folks have been trailblazing the technology and I have been reading Kevin Hoffman&amp;rsquo;s medium and wascc (nee waxosuit) work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Container Registry w/ OCI</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200508/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200508/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time this week with Krustlet.
I&amp;rsquo;m working on documenting how to run Krustlet(s) alongside GKE. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a Krustlet with MicroK8s.
The Krustlet demos reference WASM assemblines stored in Azure Container Registry as OCI containers. Google Container Registry supports OCI format and so I tried (successfully) using GCR instead of AZR.
There may be an easier approach but this is how I got this working.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>