<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cloud-monitoring on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/cloud-monitoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cloud-monitoring on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/cloud-monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Metric Diagnostics and Metric Data Ingested</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/230425/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/230425/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on an efficiency drive with Cloud Logging and Cloud Monitoring.
With regards Cloud Logging, I&amp;rsquo;m contemplating (!) eliminating almost all log storage. As it is I&amp;rsquo;ve buzz cut log storage with a _Default sink that has comprehensive sets of NOT LOG_ID(X) inclusion and exclusion filters. As I was doing so, I began to wonder why I need to pay for the storage of much logging. There&amp;rsquo;s the comfort from knowing that everything you may ever need is being logged (at least for 30 days) but there&amp;rsquo;s also the costs that that entails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Monitoring Alerting to send Pushover notifications</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220514/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220514/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Artifacts Pushover Caveat Cloud Monitoring Webhook Cloud Functions Cloud Run Artifacts GitHub: go-gcp-pushover-notificationchannel Image: ghcr.io/dazwilkin/go-gcp-pushover-notificationchannel:220515 Pushover Logging in to your Pushover account, you will be presented with a summary|dashboard page that includes Your User Key. Copy the value of this key into a variable called PUSHOVER_USER
Create New Application|API Token
Pushover API has a Pushing Messages method. The documentation describes the format of the HTTP Request. It must be a POST using TLS (https://) to https://api.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
