<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vultr on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/vultr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vultr on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/vultr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secure (TLS) gRPC services with VKE</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220603/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220603/</guid>
      <description>NOTE cert-manager is a better solution to what follows.
I&amp;rsquo;ve a need to deploy a Vultr Kubernetes Engine (VKE) cluster on a daily basis (create and delete within a few hours) and expose (securely|TLS) a gRPC service.
I have an existing solution Automatic Certs w/ Golang gRPC service on Compute Engine that combines a gRPC Healthchecking and an ACME service and decided to reuse this.
In order for it work, we need:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vultr CLI and JSON output</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220602/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220602/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve begun exploring Vultr after the company announced a managed Kubernetes offering Vultr Kubernetes Engine (VKE).
In my brief experience, it&amp;rsquo;s a decent platform and its CLI vultr-cli is mostly (!) good. The CLI has a limitation in that command output is text formatted and this makes it challenging to parse the output when scripting.
NOTE The Vultr developers have a branch rewrite that includes a solution to this problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus Exporters for fly.io and Vultr</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220520/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220520/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a roll building utilities this week. I developed a Service Health dashboard for my &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo;, a Prometheus Exporter for Fly.io and today, a Prometheus Exporter for Vultr. This is motivated by the fear that I will forget a deployed Cloud resource and incur a horrible bill.
I&amp;rsquo;ve no written several Prometheus Exporters for cloud platforms:
Prometheus Exporter for GCP Prometheus Exporter for Linode Prometheus Exporter for Fly.io Prometheus Exporter for Vultr Each of them monitors resource deployments and produces resource count metrics that can be scraped by Prometheus and alerted with Alertmanager.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
