<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Go on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Go on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PyPi Transparency</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190926/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190926/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been noodling around with another Trillian personality.
Another in a theme that interests me in providing tamperproof logs for the packages in the popular package management registries.
The Golang team recently announced Go Module Mirror which is built atop Trillian. It seems to me that all the package registries (Go Modules, npm, Maven, NuGet etc.) would benefit from tamperproof logs hosted by a trusted 3rd-party.
As you may have guessed, PyPi Transparency is a log for PyPi packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Functions Simple(st) HTTP Multi-host Proxy</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190918/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 12:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190918/</guid>
      <description>Tweaked yesterday&#39;s solution so that it will randomly select one from several hosts with which it&#39;s configured.
package proxy import ( &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;math/rand&amp;#34; &amp;#34;net/http&amp;#34; &amp;#34;net/url&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;strings&amp;#34; &amp;#34;time&amp;#34; ) func robin() { hostsList := os.Getenv(&amp;#34;PROXY_HOST&amp;#34;) if hostsList == &amp;#34;&amp;#34; { log.Fatal(&amp;#34;&amp;#39;PROXY_HOST&amp;#39; environment variable should contain comma-separated list of hosts&amp;#34;) } // Comma-separated lists of hosts  hosts := strings.Split(hostsList, &amp;#34;,&amp;#34;) urls := make([]*url.URL, len(hosts)) for i, host := range hosts { var origin = Endpoint{ Host: host, Port: os.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Functions Simple(st) HTTP Proxy</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190917/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 12:41:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190917/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m investigating the use of LetsEncrypt for gRPC services. I found this straightforward post by Scott Devoid and am going to try this approach.
Before I can do that, I need to be able to publish services (make them Internet-accessible) and would like to try to continue to use GCP for free.
Some time ago, I wrote about using the excellent Microk8s on GCP. Using an f1-micro, I&#39;m hoping (!) to stay within the Compute Engine free tier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pypi-transparency</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190907/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 13:07:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190907/</guid>
      <description>The goal of pypi-transparency is very similar to the underlying motivation for the Golang team&#39;s Checksum Database (also built with Trillian).
Even though, PyPi provides hashes of the content of packages it hosts, the developer must trust that PyPi&#39;s data is consistent. One ambition with pypi-transparency is to provide a companion, tamperproof log of PyPi package files in order to provide a double-check of these hashes.
It is important to understand what this does (and does not) provide.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>