<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pypi-Transparency on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/pypi-transparency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pypi-Transparency on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 13:07:44 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/pypi-transparency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>pypi-transparency</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190907/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 13:07:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190907/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of pypi-transparency is very similar to the underlying motivation for the Golang team&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://sum.golang.org/&#34;&gt;Checksum Database&lt;/a&gt; (also built with Trillian).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org&#34;&gt;PyPi&lt;/a&gt; provides hashes of the content of packages it hosts, the developer must trust that PyPi&amp;rsquo;s data is consistent. One ambition with pypi-transparency is to provide a companion, tamperproof log of PyPi package files in order to provide a double-check of these hashes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is important to understand what this does (and does not) provide. There&amp;rsquo;s no validation of a package&amp;rsquo;s content. The only calculation is that, on first observation, a SHA-256 hash is computed of the package&amp;rsquo;s content and the hash is recorded. If the package is subsequently altered, it&amp;rsquo;s very probable that the hash will change and this provides a signal to the user that the package&amp;rsquo;s contents has changed. Because pypi-transparency uses a tamperproof log, it&amp;rsquo;s very difficult to update the hash recorded in the tamperproof log, to reflect this change. Corrolary: pypi-transparency will record the hashes of packages that include malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
