<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gRPC on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/grpc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gRPC on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/grpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Remotely invoking WASM functions using gRPC and waPC</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200717/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200717/</guid>
      <description>Following on from waPC &amp;amp; Protobufs, I can now remotely invoke (arbitrary) WASM functions:
Client:
The logging isn&amp;rsquo;t perfectly clear but, the client gets (a previously added) WASM binary from the server (using the SHA-256 of the WASM binary as a unique identifier). The result includes metadata that includes a protobuf descriptor of the WASM binary&amp;rsquo;s functions. The descriptor defines gRPC services (that represent the WASM functions) with input (parameters) and output (results) messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust implementation of Crate Transparency using Google Trillian</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200429/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200429/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been hacking on a Rust-based transparent application for Google Trillian. As appears to be my fixation, this personality is for another package manager. This time, Rust&amp;rsquo;s Crates often found in crates.io which is Rust&amp;rsquo;s Package Registry. I discussed this project earlier this month Rust Crate Transparency &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Rust SDK for Google Trillian and and earlier approach for Python&amp;rsquo;s packages with pypi-transparency.
This time, of course, I&amp;rsquo;m using Rust. And, by way of a first for me, for the gRPC server implementation (aka &amp;ldquo;personality&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust Crate Transparency &amp;&amp; Rust SDK for Google Trillian</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200403/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200403/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m noodling the utility of a Transparency solution for Rust Crates. When developers push crates to Cargo, a bunch of metadata is associated with the crate. E.g. protobuf. As with Golang Modules, Python packages on PyPi etc., there appears to be utility in making tamperproof recordings of these publications. Then, other developers may confirm that a crate pulled from cates.io is highly unlikely to have been changed.
On Linux, Cargo stores downloaded crates under ${HOME}/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Trillian on Cloud Run</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200326/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200326/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written previously (Google Trillian for Noobs) about Google&amp;rsquo;s interesting project Trillian and about some of the &amp;ldquo;personalities&amp;rdquo; (e.g. PyPi Transparency) that I&amp;rsquo;ve build using it.
Having gone slight cra-cra on Cloud Run and gRPC this week with Golang gRPC Cloud Run and gRPC, Cloud Run &amp;amp; Endpoints, I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to deploy Trillian and a personality to Cloud Run.
It mostly (!) works :-)
At the end of the post, I&amp;rsquo;ve summarized creating a Cloud SQL instance to host the Trillian data(base).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC, Cloud Run &amp; Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200325/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200325/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;3 Google but there&amp;rsquo;s quite often an assumption that we&amp;rsquo;re all sitting around the engineering table and, of course, we&amp;rsquo;re not.
Cloud Endpoints is a powerful offering but &amp;ndash; IMO &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s super confusing to understand and complex to deploy.
If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with the motivations behind service meshes (e.g. Istio), Cloud Endpoints fits in a similar niche (&amp;ldquo;neesh&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;nitch&amp;rdquo;?). The underlying ambition is that, developers can take existing code and by adding a proxy (or sidecar), general-purpose abstractions, security, logging etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang gRPC Cloud Run</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200320/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200320/</guid>
      <description>Update: 2020-03-24: Since writing this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed Golang and Rust samples to Google&amp;rsquo;s project. I recommend you start there.
 Google explained how to run gRPC servers with Cloud Run. The examples are good but only Python and Node.JS:
 gRPC comes to Cloud Run gRPC in Google Cloud Run  Missing Golang&amp;hellip;. until now ;-)
I had problems with 1.14 and so I&amp;rsquo;m using 1.13.
Project structure I&amp;rsquo;ll tidy up my repo but the code may be found:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Functions Simple(st) HTTP Multi-host Proxy</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190918/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 12:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190918/</guid>
      <description>Tweaked yesterday&amp;rsquo;s solution so that it will randomly select one from several hosts with which it&amp;rsquo;s configured.
package proxy import ( &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;math/rand&amp;#34; &amp;#34;net/http&amp;#34; &amp;#34;net/url&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;strings&amp;#34; &amp;#34;time&amp;#34; ) func robin() { hostsList := os.Getenv(&amp;#34;PROXY_HOST&amp;#34;) if hostsList == &amp;#34;&amp;#34; { log.Fatal(&amp;#34;&amp;#39;PROXY_HOST&amp;#39; environment variable should contain comma-separated list of hosts&amp;#34;) } // Comma-separated lists of hosts  hosts := strings.Split(hostsList, &amp;#34;,&amp;#34;) urls := make([]*url.URL, len(hosts)) for i, host := range hosts { var origin = Endpoint{ Host: host, Port: os.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Functions Simple(st) HTTP Proxy</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190917/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 12:41:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/190917/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m investigating the use of LetsEncrypt for gRPC services. I found this straightforward post by Scott Devoid and am going to try this approach.
Before I can do that, I need to be able to publish services (make them Internet-accessible) and would like to try to continue to use GCP for free.
Some time ago, I wrote about using the excellent Microk8s on GCP. Using an f1-micro, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping (!) to stay within the Compute Engine free tier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>