<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Compute Engine on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/compute-engine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Compute Engine on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/compute-engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Google&#39;s Public Certificate Authority with Golang autocert</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220421/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220421/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I wrote about using Automatic Certs w/ Golang gRPC service on Compute Engine. That solution uses ACME with (the wonderful) Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt. Google is offering a private preview of Automate Public Certificates Lifecycle Management via RFC 8555 (ACME) and, because I&amp;rsquo;m using Google Cloud Platform extensively to build a &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; and I think it would be useful to have a backup to Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give the solution a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Certs w/ Golang gRPC service on Compute Engine</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/211130/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/211130/</guid>
      <description>I needed to deploy a healthcheck-enabled gRPC TLS-enabled service. Fortunately, most (all?) of the SDKs include an implementation, e.g. Golang has grpc-go/health.
I learned in my travels that:
 DigitalOcean [App] platform does not (link) work with TLS-based gRPC apps. Fly has a regression (link) that breaks gRPC  So, I resorted to Google Cloud Platform (GCP). Although Cloud Run would be well-suited to running the gRPC app, it uses a proxy|sidecar to provision a cert for the app and I wanted to be able to (easily use a custom domain) and give myself a somewhat general-purpose solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akri</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/201113/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/201113/</guid>
      <description>For the past couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with Akri, a Microsoft (DeisLabs) project for building a connected edge with Kubernetes. Kubernetes, IoT, Rust (and Golang) make this all compelling to me.
Initially, I deployed an Akri End-to-End to MicroK8s on Google Compute Engine (link) and Digital Ocean (link). But I was interested to create me own example and so have proposed a very (!) simple HTTP-based protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>akri</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/201022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/201022/</guid>
      <description>I was very interested to read about Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s DeisLab&amp;rsquo;s latest (rust-based) Kubernetes project: akri. If I understand it correctly, it provides a mechanism to make any (IoT) device accessible to containers running within a cluster. I need to spend more time playing around with it so that I can fully understand it. I had some problems getting the End-to-End demo running on Google Compute Engine (and then I tried DigitalOcean droplet) instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a GCE Instance as an Inlets Exit Node</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200122/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200122/</guid>
      <description>The prolific Alex Ellis has a new project, Inlets.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick tutorial using Google Compute Platform&amp;rsquo;s (GCP) Compute Engine (GCE).
NB I&amp;rsquo;m using one of Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Always free&amp;rdquo; f1-micro instances but you may still pay for network *gress and storage
Assumptions I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you&amp;rsquo;ve a Google account, have used GCP and have a billing account established, i.e. the following returns at least one billing account:
gcloud beta billing accounts list If you&amp;rsquo;ve only one billing account and it&amp;rsquo;s the one you wish to use, then you can:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Cloud Platform (GCP) Exporter</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/191220/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/191220/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week I discussed a Linode Prometheus Exporter.
I added metrics for Digital Ocean&amp;rsquo;s Managed Kubernetes service to @metalmatze&amp;rsquo;s Digital Ocean Exporter.
This left, metrics for Google Cloud Platform (GCP) which has, for many years, been my primary cloud platform. So, today I wrote Prometheus Exporter for Google Cloud Platform.
All 3 of these exporters follow the template laid down by @metalmatze and, because each of these services has a well-written Golang SDK, it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to implement an exporter for each of them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
