<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eventarc on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/eventarc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eventarc on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0-DEV</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/eventarc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Cloud Events protobufs and SDKs</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/240405/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/240405/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about Ackal&amp;rsquo;s use of Firestore and subscribing to Firestore document CRUD events:&#xA;Routing Firestore events to GKE with Eventarc Cloud Firestore Triggers in Golang using Firestore triggers I find Google&amp;rsquo;s Eventarc documentation to be confusing and, in typical Google fashion, even though open-sourced, you often need to do some legwork to find relevant sources, viz:&#xA;Google&amp;rsquo;s Protobufs for Eventarc (using cloudevents) google-cloudevents1 Convenience (since you can generate these using protoc) language-specific types generated from the above e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Routing Firestore events to GKE with Eventarc</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/230530/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/230530/</guid>
      <description>Google announced Firestore &amp;hellip; integration with Eventarc. Ackal uses Firestore to persist Customer and Check information and it uses Google Cloud Firestore Triggers to handle events on these document types.&#xA;Eventarc feels like the strategic future of eventing in Google Cloud and I&amp;rsquo;ve been concerned since adopting the technology that Google would abandon Google Cloud Firestore Triggers.&#xA;For this reason, when I saw last week&amp;rsquo;s announcement, I thought I should evaluate the mechanism and this blog post is a summary of that work.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
