<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>webhook on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/webhook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in webhook on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/webhook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tailscale Webhook </title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/221114/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/221114/</guid>
      <description>[Tailscale] is really good. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it as a virtual private network to span 2 home networks and to securely (!) access my hosts when I&amp;rsquo;m remote.
Recently Tailscale added Webhook functionality to permit processing subscribed-to (Tailscale) events. I&amp;rsquo;m always a sucker for a webhook ;-)
I had some problems getting Tailscale&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Test endpoint&amp;rdquo; to POST events to my mashup (see below) server.
So, here&amp;rsquo;s a curl equivalent:
URL=&amp;#34;&amp;#34; # Webhook URL https://{machine}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Monitoring Alerting to send Pushover notifications</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220514/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220514/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Artifacts Pushover Caveat Cloud Monitoring Webhook Cloud Functions Cloud Run Artifacts GitHub: go-gcp-pushover-notificationchannel Image: ghcr.io/dazwilkin/go-gcp-pushover-notificationchannel:220515 Pushover Logging in to your Pushover account, you will be presented with a summary|dashboard page that includes Your User Key. Copy the value of this key into a variable called PUSHOVER_USER
Create New Application|API Token
Pushover API has a Pushing Messages method. The documentation describes the format of the HTTP Request. It must be a POST using TLS (https://) to https://api.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes cert-manager</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/210108/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/210108/</guid>
      <description>I developed an admission webhook for Akri, twice (Golang, Rust). I naively followed other examples for the generation of the certificates, created a 1.20 cluster and broke that process.
I&amp;rsquo;d briefly considered using cert-manager recently but quickly abandoned the idea thinking it would be onerous and unnecessary complexity for little-old-me. I was wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s excellent and I recommend it highly.
I won&amp;rsquo;t reproduce the v1beta1 and v1 examples from the Stackoverflow question as they should be self-explanatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Webhooks</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/201229/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/201229/</guid>
      <description>I spent some time last week writing my first admission webhook for Kubernetes. I wrote the handler in Golang because I&amp;rsquo;m most familiar with Golang and because, as Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; native language, I was more confident that the necessary SDKs would exist and that the documentation would likely use Golang by default. I struggled to find useful documentation and so this post is to help you (and me!) remember how to do this next time!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
