<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>protobufs on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/protobufs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in protobufs on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/protobufs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WASM Transparency</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200817/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200817/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with a proof-of-concept combining WASM and Trillian. The hypothesis was to explore using WASM as a form of chaincode with Trillian. The project works but it&amp;rsquo;s far from being a chaincode-like solution.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a couple of (trivial) examples and then I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what&amp;rsquo;s going on and how it&amp;rsquo;s implemented.
2020/08/14 18:42:17 [main:loop:dynamic-invoke] Method: mul 2020/08/14 18:42:17 [random:New] Message 2020/08/14 18:42:17 [random:New] Float32 2020/08/14 18:42:17 [random:New] Float32 2020/08/14 18:42:17 [random:New] Message 2020/08/14 18:42:17 [random:New] Float32 2020/08/14 18:42:17 [random:New] Float32 2020/08/14 18:42:17 [Client:Invoke] Metadata: complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remotely invoking WASM functions using gRPC and waPC</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200717/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200717/</guid>
      <description>Following on from waPC &amp;amp; Protobufs, I can now remotely invoke (arbitrary) WASM functions:
Client:
The logging isn&amp;rsquo;t perfectly clear but, the client gets (a previously added) WASM binary from the server (using the SHA-256 of the WASM binary as a unique identifier). The result includes metadata that includes a protobuf descriptor of the WASM binary&amp;rsquo;s functions. The descriptor defines gRPC services (that represent the WASM functions) with input (parameters) and output (results) messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Protobuf APIv2</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200630/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200630/</guid>
      <description>Google has a new Golang Protobuf API, APIv2 (google.golang.org/protobuf) superseding APIv1 (github.com/golang/protobuf). If your code is importing github.com/golang/protobuf, you&amp;rsquo;re using APIv2. Otherwise, you should consult with the docs because Google reimplemented APIv1 atop APIv2. One challenge this caused me, as someone who does not use protobufs and gRPC on a daily basis, is that gRPC (code-generation) is being removed from the (Golang) protoc-gen-go, the Golang plugin that generates gRPC service bindings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WASM Cloud Functions</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200617/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200617/</guid>
      <description>Following on from waPC &amp;amp; Protobufs and a question on Stack Overflow about Cloud Functions, I was compelled to try running WASM on Cloud Functions no JavaScript.
I wanted to reuse the WASM waPC functions that I&amp;rsquo;d written in Rust as described in the other post. Cloud Functions does not (yet!?) provide a Rust runtime and so I&amp;rsquo;m using the waPC Host for Go in this example.
It works!
PARAMS=$(printf &amp;#39;{&amp;#34;a&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;real&amp;#34;:39,&amp;#34;imag&amp;#34;:3},&amp;#34;b&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;real&amp;#34;:39,&amp;#34;imag&amp;#34;:3}}&amp;#39; | base64) TOKEN=$(gcloud auth print-identity-token) echo &amp;#34;{ \&amp;#34;filename\&amp;#34;:\&amp;#34;complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>waPC &amp; Protobufs</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200612/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200612/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m hacking around with a solution that combines WASM and Google Trillian.
Ultimately, I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to ship WASM (binaries) to a Trillian personality and then invoke (exported) functions on them. Some this was borne from the interesting exploration of Krustlet and its application of wascc.
I&amp;rsquo;m still booting into WASM but it&amp;rsquo;s a very interesting technology that has most interesting potential outside the browser. Some folks have been trailblazing the technology and I have been reading Kevin Hoffman&amp;rsquo;s medium and wascc (nee waxosuit) work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust implementation of Crate Transparency using Google Trillian</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200429/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200429/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been hacking on a Rust-based transparent application for Google Trillian. As appears to be my fixation, this personality is for another package manager. This time, Rust&amp;rsquo;s Crates often found in crates.io which is Rust&amp;rsquo;s Package Registry. I discussed this project earlier this month Rust Crate Transparency &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Rust SDK for Google Trillian and and earlier approach for Python&amp;rsquo;s packages with pypi-transparency.
This time, of course, I&amp;rsquo;m using Rust. And, by way of a first for me, for the gRPC server implementation (aka &amp;ldquo;personality&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC, Cloud Run &amp; Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200325/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200325/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;3 Google but there&amp;rsquo;s quite often an assumption that we&amp;rsquo;re all sitting around the engineering table and, of course, we&amp;rsquo;re not.
Cloud Endpoints is a powerful offering but &amp;ndash; IMO &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s super confusing to understand and complex to deploy.
If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with the motivations behind service meshes (e.g. Istio), Cloud Endpoints fits in a similar niche (&amp;ldquo;neesh&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;nitch&amp;rdquo;?). The underlying ambition is that, developers can take existing code and by adding a proxy (or sidecar), general-purpose abstractions, security, logging etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang gRPC Cloud Run</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200320/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200320/</guid>
      <description>Update: 2020-03-24: Since writing this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed Golang and Rust samples to Google&amp;rsquo;s project. I recommend you start there.
 Google explained how to run gRPC servers with Cloud Run. The examples are good but only Python and Node.JS:
 gRPC comes to Cloud Run gRPC in Google Cloud Run  Missing Golang&amp;hellip;. until now ;-)
I had problems with 1.14 and so I&amp;rsquo;m using 1.13.
Project structure I&amp;rsquo;ll tidy up my repo but the code may be found:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s New Golang SDK for Protobufs</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200310/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/200310/</guid>
      <description>Google has released a new Golang SDK for protobuf. In the [announcement], a useful tool to redact properties is described. If like me, this is somewhat novel to you, here&amp;rsquo;s a mashup using Google&amp;rsquo;s Protocol Buffer Basics w/ redaction.
To be very clear, as it&amp;rsquo;s an important distinction:
   Version Repo Docs     v2 google.golang.org/protobuf Docs   v1 github.com/golang/protobuf Docs    Project Here&amp;rsquo;s my project structure:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
