<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Service-Discovery on (p)retired</title>
    <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/service-discovery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Service-Discovery on (p)retired</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/tags/service-discovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus HTTP Service Discovery of Cloud Run services</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220225/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/220225/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago, I wrote about using Prometheus Service Discovery w/ Consul for Cloud Run and also Scraping metrics exposed by Google Cloud Run services that require authentication. Both solutions remain viable but they didn&amp;rsquo;t address another use case for Prometheus and Cloud Run services that I have with a &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; that I&amp;rsquo;ve been building.&#xA;In this scenario, I want to:&#xA;Configure Prometheus to scrape Cloud Run service metrics Discover Cloud Run services dynamically Authenticate to Cloud Run using Firebase Auth ID tokens These requirements and &amp;ndash; one other &amp;ndash; present several challenges:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consul discovers Google Cloud Run</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/210520/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/210520/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a basic discoverer of Google Cloud Run services. This is for a project and it extends work done in some previous posts to Multiplex gRPC and Prometheus with Cloud Run and to use Consul for Prometheus service discovery.&#xA;This solution:&#xA;Accepts a set of Google Cloud Platform (GCP) projects Trawls them for Cloud Run services Assumes that the services expose Prometheus metrics on :443/metrics Relabels the services Surfaces any discovered Cloud Run services&amp;rsquo; metrics in Prometheus You&amp;rsquo;ll need Docker and Docker Compose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus Service Discovery w/ Consul for Cloud Run</title>
      <link>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/210419/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pretired.dazwilkin.com/posts/210419/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a project that will programmatically create Google Cloud Run services and I want to be able to dynamically discover these services using Prometheus.&#xA;This is one solution.&#xA;NOTE Google Cloud Run is the service I&amp;rsquo;m using, but the principle described herein applies to any runtime service that you&amp;rsquo;d wish to use.&#xA;Why is this challenging? IIUC, it&amp;rsquo;s primarily because Prometheus has a limited set of plugins for service discovery, see the sections that include _sd_ in Prometheus Configuration documentation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
